PARAMJIT SINGH



E-mail: ps.singhjit@qmail.com Phone: (647)8329212 GitHub: https://github.com/ps-singhjit

Website: https://ps-singhjit.github.io/MyIntro/

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY:

Over 10 years of progressive experience in Quality Assurance Software Testing, Manual, Robotic Process Automation (RPA) and Automated testing on Web based, Window based, APIs/Webservices and Mobile applications for clients in Banking, Insurance and Telecom industries. Thorough knowledge of all phases of Software Development Life Cycle (SDLC), Software Testing Life Cycle (STLC) and Defect Life Cycle (DLC) in Agile and Waterfall development environment.

Working experience with various Test management tools (HP QC/ALM, Jira, Service Now etc.) and Automation tools (UFT, Selenium, Qualitia, Robot, Katalon Studio, UiPath Studio, Eggplant etc.). Experience in feasibility study, PoC, and framework design for automated testing. Used GIT/Bit Bucket and HP ALM for version controlling and maintaining scripts and test resources.

Seeking an opportunity as an Automation QA Analyst to utilize relevant experience in test development and maintenance.

TECHNICAL SKILLS:

- Programming Languages: Java, Python, JavaScript, Gherkins and Groovy.
- **Testing Tools:** HP ALM, UFT, JIRA, Selenium, Qualitia, Katalon Studio, Postman, and UiPath Studio.
- **Frameworks:** TestNG, Cucumber, Robot, Keyword and Data driven.
- ❖ IDE: VS Code, Eclipse, PyCharm, RIDE and UFT.
- Source Code Management (SCM) Tools: Bit Bucket, GitHub, GitLab.
- **❖ DOM Concepts:** HTML, XML, JSON.
- **Scripting Languages:** VB Script, JavaScript, and Sense Talk.
- ❖ Databases: SQL Server 2005/2008, Oracle, NoSQL, MongoDB.
- Operating Systems: Windows 7/8/10, LINUX/UNIX, OS X, iOS, Android, Blackberry OS.
- **❖ Browsers:** IE, Edge, Chrome, Firefox, Safari.
- ❖ Microsoft Suite: MS Office Word, Excel, Power Point, Outlook.

SUMMARY OF RESPONSIBILITIES:

- Worked on testing various APIs involved in payment system.
- Used Python and core Java-Maven-TestNG, REST Assured to perform API testing.
- Integrated scripts with MongoDB to validate error logs.
- Familiarity with IB MQ and Apache Kafka technology.
- Familiarity with Continuous integration (CI/CD) using Jenkins.
- Successfully analysed regression suite and did feasibility study for automated execution.
- Prepared a PoC for the applications using different tools (e.g., HP UFT, Selenium, Robot, Cucumber, Qualitia and Eggplant) to satisfy different project needs.
- Developed new frameworks for various applications while working in ACOE team for the future projects.
- ❖ Experience in working with various automation frameworks. Such as: Keywork driven, Hybrid, Cucumber with core Java and Python, Robot Framework, TestNG.
- ❖ Developed a hybrid framework where the script was able to create its own expected results and verify actual result against it.
- Contributed to keywords, libraries, script generation and improving frameworks.
- Maintained scripts during different execution cycles and updated regression suite as per new requirements.
- Used OTA (Open Test Architecture) to streamline various test activities. Such as: automated data preparation from database, uploading resources to HP ALM, batch runner, ALM resource extractor, ALM script extractor, automatic email generation etc.
- Trained and mentored Functional Testers to contribute to Automation development and maintenance.
- Used GIT/Bit Bucket to incorporate version controlling for scripts and results.

- ❖ Having hands-on in Robotic Process Automation (RPA) using UiPath studio tool.
- Developed a utility to compare PDFs using UFT and Selenium Java.
- Successfully tested applications on different mobile devices such as Android phones and tablets, iPhone, and iPad.
- Performed POC for different projects and provided training to stake holders.
- ❖ Maintained and documented the whole process in Atlassian Confluence.
- Created policies in Guidewire for clients in Auto, Home and Business (P&C) as part of test data setup.
- ❖ Documented Test cases for application based on the Test Scenarios and Use cases, in HP Quality Center (QC/ALM) for proper test management.

WORK EXPERIENCE:

Employer: Teacup Tech Systems Client: Medavie Blue Cross, Moncton, NBJune 2021 – Present

June 2021 – Present

Role: Automation Test Lead Project: Government Portals

The project deals with different aspects of Health Insurance including registration, claim process, documents etc. Immigrants in Canada who are eligible for health benefits take advantage of Government services through these portals.

The project includes automating various government UI portals. The test frameworks in use are – WebdriverIO, JavaScript, NodeJS with BDD Gherkins /Cucumber. The source and CI/CD have been maintained in GitLab.

Environment: NodeJS, WebdriverIO, GIT Lab, JavaScript, TypeScript, Visual Studio Code, HP ALM, JIRA, Jenkins, REST Assured, Axios, Spring Boot.

Employer: Tata Consultancy Services (TCS)

Jan 2017 – May 2021 Jan 2021 – May 2021

Client: RBC, Toronto (TCS)
Role: Automation Test Lead, API

Project: AML and Payments

There are regulations for Money Laundering and Terrorist Financing Act passed from the Department of Finance. The amended Travel Rule now requires additional details on the client's end. The project deals with various combinations of SWIFT and Non-SWIFT transactions details verifications end to end.

The project includes automating various transaction flows distributed among different applications. The test frameworks in use are – Java, Maven and TestNG, Java with BDD Gherkins /Cucumber, Robot Framework with RIDE, Python with Gherkins/ Cucumber. The source has been maintained in GIT Hub.

Environment: Apache Kafka, MQ, REST Assured, Maven, Java, Python, Spring Boot, MongoDB, IBM® Db2, HP ALM, GIT/GIT Hub, Jenkins.

Client: WSIB, Toronto (TCS)

Sep 2020 - Dec2020

Role: Senior Automation Analyst Project: Regression for Guidewire

The project deals with different modules of Guidewire, including Policy center, Billing center, Claims center. Mostly dealing with web-based application, Automation is done using Selenium with Maven, TestNG framework using a keyword driver approach.

Environment: Guidewire, Selenium, Maven, Java, HP ALM, GIT/Bit Bucket.

Client: CIBC, Toronto (TCS)

Nov 2019 - Aug2020

Role: QA Automation Developer

Project: DCCT, IVR, Verint, Cards (MasterCard/Visa) Automation

This project includes a bunch of applications involved in IVR system. Most of it includes Desktop applications. The Test suite is developed using Qualitia and UFT. The other part of the project deals with Credit cards. The UI automation suites are developed and maintained in Robot Framework. The source has been maintained in GIT Hub. POCs were also performed to check feasibility of other frameworks, majorly Python with Cucumber and Katalon Studio.

Environment: UFT 14.50, HP ALM, GIT/Bit Bucket, Confluence, Qualitia, Robot Framework, Eclipse, Katalon Studio, Jenkins.

Client: BMO, Toronto (TCS)

Jan 2017 - Nov 2019

Role: Automation QA Analyst

Project: UFT Upgrade and ALM Disintegration

Due to some changes in products portfolio, organization is trying to fine tune its existing tools armory. One of the affected tools duo is UFT and ALM. As the management has decided to get rid of ALM in the organization, the decision has been made to bring in new set of tools. This triggered an initiative to move all UFT Frameworks and Scripts on a working platform.

Environment: UFT 14.50, HP ALM, .Net, Java, GIT/Bit Bucket, Confluence.

Project: Forms Check List (FCL)

To ensure compliance with the new proposed amendments surrounding the Proceeds of Crime (Money Laundering), Terrorist Financing Act (PC Act), and Proceeds of Crime (Money Laundering) Regulations (PCMLTFR), Bank of Montreal (BMO) has been obligated to collect additional information regarding its clients; most notably Politically Exposed Domestic Persons (PEDPS) and Politically Exposed Foreign Persons (PEFPs) and International Organization PEP (IO PEP). FCL is a Windows based application dealing with all the forms, required from the client end to ensure the compliance with different types of investment accounts.

Environment: .Net, Java, Oracle, VBA, MS Office 2013, HP UFT, SharePoint, IE11.

Project: Client Statement Redesign

This project was a common part of many applications which are responsible to create client statements for different investments. It deals with verifying client statements generated in PDF format, depending on various conditions and investment types. The objective of the project was to highlight the differences in the PDF and adding relevant comments to it. The objective also included verifying any changes in Fonts of the PDF statements. The successful automation has benefited many other projects in terms of the reliability and total time of execution. **Environment:** Adobe Acrobat DC, Selenium, Java, HP UFT, MS Office 2013, SharePoint, IE11.

Client: The Co-operators, Guelph Role: QA Analyst (Web/Mobile Tester)

Aug 2016 – Dec 2016

Project: Online Services-Client Preference Center and Mobile App

The Co-operators Group Limited is a leading Canadian multi-product insurance and financial service co-operative. They operate in three core areas: Property and Casualty insurance, Life insurance and Institutional investments. This web-based application provides its customers an option to do online/web registration for their existing policy and set and edit their preferences. Mobile app was also developed which worked as wrapper app for all the functionalities provided by the web application.

Environment: C#, .Net, Service first, MS Office 2013, HP UFT, Service First, Guidewire Policy center, SharePoint, OKTA, Oracle PeopleSoft Enterprise (ECM), WebSphere Customer Center, Android, iPhone & iPad, IE11, Chrome and Firefox.

Client: Wind Mobile, Toronto

Sep 2014 – April 2016

Role: QA Analyst

Project: My Account Mobile Application and Web Application

My Account Mobile Application and Web Application provide access to information relating to customer's services such as checking account balance, wallet balance, making payment using credit, debit card, Interac or top up code/coupons, view billing and payment history, setup preauthorized payments, add or remove add-ons, change plans, enable, or disable international calling or roaming, check and compare service usage history, update account information etc.

Environment: Java, .Net, Quality Center, MS Office, MS SQL Server 2008 R2, Android, iPhone & iPad, Windows, Blackberry.

Client: Wawanesa Insurance, Toronto

Feb 2013 – Aug 2014

ps.singhjit@gmail.com Page 3 of 4 Ph: 6478329212

Role: Software Quality Assurance Analyst Project: WWI Web Payment and Commission

Wawanesa insurance is a Canadian, multi-product insurance with four core areas of operation Automobile, Home, Business and Farm Insurance (Property & Casualty and Commercial Lines). This web-based application provides its customers an option to do online/web registration for any new product (e.g., any new vehicle, home or business.). Payment/Billing (Web based Portal) and Commission centre upgrade (Client Server) – project was to design, develop and test the upgrade release of Payment centre as well as required Oracle upgrade in Java based application.

Environment: QC, QTP, SQL, .Net, Java, Red Hat Linux, UNIX, Oracle Database.

Client: ICICI Bank, India Feb 2009 – May 2011

Position Title: Software Tester

Project: ICICI Bank Mobile Banking Application

Client Online Banking Application – iMobile, provides access to information relating to Banking Online Services provided by ICICI Bank to View daily customer transactions, Current and Previous customer statements, Transfer funds from Current and Savings accounts, Order Cheques, Shop, Bill payments. They provide ICICI Bank mobile online banking application for Android, I-Phone and Blackberry.

Environment: IBM WebSphere Application Server, Quality Center 10.0, Oracle 10g, MS Office 2003, Symbian, Android, iOS, Blackberry.

CERTIFICATIONS:

- Scrum Fundamentals Certified (SFC)
- ❖ ISTQB CSTB Certified
- Completed PMI ACP (Agile Certified Practitioner) Training
- Certificate of Completion Katalon Studio
- Certificate of Completion GIT Fundamentals
- Certificate of Completion Robotic Process Automation (RPA) using UiPath

EDUCATION:

- Post Graduate Diploma in Wireless Networking, George Brown College, Toronto, Canada
- Master of Business Administration in Finance and Marketing, IIPM, Hyderabad, India/ International Management Institute (IMI), Brussels, Belgium
- **❖ Bachelor of Engineering in Computer Science & Engineering,** V.T. University, Karnataka, India **ADMIRATIONS:**
 - * Recognised by client for automating a PDF comparison project for very specific requirements. The automation helped length of each cycle of project to be drastically reduced from 4 weeks and 5 team members to 2 days and 2 team members, hence positively impacting the bottom line.